### EMMANUEL KUFFOUR OSEI

Email: oseikuffouremmanuel77@gmail.com

**Address**: Kumasi, Ghana **Phone**: +233 (0) 55-206-6825

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/ikuffourosei">https://github.com/ikuffourosei</a>

I am focused on addressing complex environmental issues to aid in governmental policy formation and enforcement. With proven research skills and relevant experience in GIS, Python Programming and spatial data analysis, I am confident I will succeed in graduate school to achieve my career goal.

## **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science in Geomatic Engineering**

Aug 2018 – Sep 2022

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology (KNUST), Kumasi, Ghana

Thesis: Interactive Web Map of KNUST campus To Facilitate Navigation

Technologies: QGIS, JavaScript (Leaflet Library)

### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

Geographic Information Science & Systems (GIS), Remote Sensing, Geospatial Data Visualization, Land Use Monitoring, Transportation and Urban Analytics.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Building and Roads Research Institute (BRRI) – Kumasi, Ghana Research Assistant (Supervisor: Ing. Mrs. Emmanuella A. Asamoah) (Nov 2022 – Oct 2023)

- Analysis of spatiotemporal distribution of traffic accidents to identify high-risk areas and times for implementing safety measures.
- Mapping and Visualization of accident data in a web map using Leaflet (Open-Source JavaScript Library) and QGIS to build the map, and using Google Earth Engine for extracting geographical data.
- Crash Prediction Models at Intersections of Multi-lane Highways using QGIS and Python.
- Assisted other divisions with their research by finding the research gaps in the "Affordable Housing Project in Ghana".

# Department of Urban Roads (DUR) – Kumasi, Ghana Intern (Supervisor: Ing. Mrs. Kennyworth Baaba Buckson)

(Oct 2021 – Dec 2021)

- Assisted with the design and development of the 'New Kumasi' project using AutoCAD to facilitate better operations and efficiency of urban roads in Kumasi.
- Estimated the Annual Average Daily Traffic (AADT) to determine road capacities and design infrastructure that effectively accommodates the traffic volume.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Joshob Construction Company Limited – Kumasi Ghana Geomatic Engineer

(Apr 2024 – Present)

- Horizontal and Vertical road Setting out
- Setting out drains and culverts.
- Establishing controls (benchmarks) for leveling and GPS works.
- Estimating cut/fill volumes of earthworks, concrete, and asphalt materials.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **GIS and Mapping:** Google Earth Engine, QGIS, ArcGIS/ArcMap
- Data Analysis and Prediction: Python, Crash Data Analysis
- Engineering and Surveying: AutoCAD, GPS, Leveling

### **CERTIFICATES**

• Software Engineering (Online) – ALX

Key Skills: Python Programming, Data Structures, Algorithms, Software Development Lifecycle, Bash Scripting and Automation, Testing.